For many white-collar workers around the world, the recent pandemic has meant having to work from home.
对于全球许多白领员工而言，近年来的疫情意味着他们不得不居家办公。
Their usual office location has been out of bounds.
他们平日里的办公地点已经禁止入内。
This means different working practices, which have advantages and disadvantages for employees.
这意味着迥然不同的工作模式，对员工而言各有利弊。
But the big question is, will they ever see their offices again?
但一个关键问题是：他们还会重返办公室吗？
Home working has made people realise what tasks they can perform at home, rather than enduring a commute to the office to do the same thing.
居家办公让人们意识到，有些工作完全可以在家完成，不必忍受通勤之苦跑去办公室做同样的事。
It has given them more time with the family; they’ve been sleeping better and have saved money by not travelling or buying lunches on the go.
居家办公让他们有了更多陪伴家人的时间，睡眠质量也有所提升，同时还省下了通勤费用和外出买午餐的开支。
And recent research suggests the majority of people working from home are just as productive.
近期研究表明，大多数居家办公的人，工作效率和在办公室时不相上下。
For some people, this could be a permanent arrangement.
对有些人来说，居家办公可能会成为一种长期安排。
In the UK, fifty of the biggest employers questioned by the BBC, have said they have no plans to return all staff to the office full-time in the near future.
在英国，英国广播公司调查的五十家大型企业均表示，近期不打算让所有员工全职返回办公室办公。
Of course, one main reason is that firms couldn’t see a way of accommodating large numbers of staff while social distancing regulations were still in place.
当然，一个主要原因是，在社交距离规定仍然生效的情况下，企业无法找到合适的办法来容纳大量员工办公。
But the BBC also heard from some smaller businesses who are deciding to abandon their offices altogether.
但英国广播公司也了解到，一些小型企业正决定彻底放弃办公场所。
Other bigger companies are also looking at shutting offices to save money as many jobs can be performed remotely.
其他大型企业也在考虑关闭办公场所来节省开支，因为许多工作都可以远程完成。
Peter Cheese, head of the Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development, told the BBC: “We’re at a moment of real change in the world of work, driven by big existential crises.”
英国特许人事与发展协会负责人彼得·奇斯向英国广播公司表示：“在重大生存危机的推动下，我们正处于职场发生真正变革的时刻。”
But this isn’t great news for everyone.
但这对所有人而言并非都是好消息。
Some employees can feel isolated at home, and there’s less opportunity to network or learn from other people, especially if they’re a new recruit.
有些员工在家办公会感到孤立无援，而且建立人脉或向他人学习的机会也会减少，新员工尤其如此。
Also, city centres may suffer most from a change in working habits.
此外，工作习惯的改变可能会对市中心造成最严重的冲击。
Shops and cafes rely on the footfall of office workers, and without them, they face closure.
商店和咖啡馆都依赖白领员工带来的客流量，失去了这些客源，它们就面临着倒闭的风险。
The future is still uncertain, which is why it may be too early to say where our desks will be permanently located.
未来仍充满不确定性，因此现在断言我们的办公桌会长期放置在何处还为时过早。
But the office of the future may be your home.
但未来的办公室，或许就是你的家。